DANIEL BAILEY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

EDUCATION

Bachelors A-Levels

Staffordshire University

Games Development 2:1

2016 - 2020

North Lindsey College

Physics B, Maths B, Psychology C

2014 - 2016

DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCE

C# & C++

- Software
- Games
- Game Engines
- OOP
- SOLID
- TCP/UDP Networking

Game Engines

- Unity 2D/3D
- Unreal Engine 4
- Console/PC
- Mobile

Web Development

- HTML
- CSS/SCSS
- JavaScript/Typescript
- React/Vue
- REST
- SQL
- .NET
- MVC
- Razor

Development Process

- Version Control (Git/GitHub)
- Azure/Devops
- Agile Methodologies (SCRUM, Kanban)
- Trello
- Microsoft Teams

PROFILE

I am a graduate of Staffordshire University with a2:1in Games Development. I am working as a Graduate Engineer at BEP Systems. I have experience using game engines, front/back end web development and programming in C#, C++, HTML, SCSS and JavaScript.

CONTACT

Location

Greater Manchester

Phone Number

07542886642

Email

danbailey.813@gmail.com

Website

danrbailey.netlify.com

References available on request

PROJECTS

Vue Calendar Holidays

- Vue/HTML/SCSS
- APIs
- Material Design

Mobile Game

- Unity
- C#
- Arcade Mobile Game
- Released to Android
- Monetized using ads and in-app purchases

Mobile Rhythm Game

- Unity
- C#
- Rhythm-Based
- Synth-wave theme
- Focus on player-retention

Puzzle Game for the Motor Impaired

- Unreal Engine 4/Unity
- C#
- C++
- Blueprints
- Single Input

Couch Co-op Party Game

- Unreal Engine 4
- C++
- Blueprints
- Local Multiplayer
- Controller Support

WORK EXPERIENCE

February 2021 - Present

Graduate Developer

BEP Systems

Manchester

July 2019 - June 2020

Team Member

Roadchef

Roadchef Stafford

January 2014 – July 2016

Chef Assistant

D'Litas Cakes and Catering

Scunthorpe